all right so it looks like we have a
good group of people
on the line here so we're just gonna dig
in and get going so thanks everybody for
joining us
today to talk through metrics and
reporting within
inventory planner and uh what other
systems you might need for kind of
related reporting and metrics to find
out what you need
so our goal today is to really
take a look at the financial health
of of your company related to inventory
how inventory
affects that what metrics you need to be
looking at and then what you can monitor
in order to improve those numbers too
so um just a bit of housekeeping
here so the webinar is being recorded so
you'll get an automatic recording of
this
afterwards i think it comes within 24
hours so
you'll get a recording of that we'll
also put it up on youtube it'll be
available there feel free to use the
chat
the q a that's at the bottom of the zoom
screen
to ask questions at any time so we have
several people from the inventory
planner team on the call they can answer
via chat in real time and then at the
end of the session
we'll also read through those and go
through screen share
as applicable just so it's on the
recording and we're kind of talking
through what that is
but i expect that there will be quite a
few questions that may be related to
your
particular situation so we've left about
15 minutes
at the end of this time so that um so
that we really have time to kind of work
through those things
and then as always we want to know what
your feedback is
was this helpful did this answer your
questions and what other topics would
you like us to cover in the future
so we do have a few webinars coming up
we have one next week
um we'll give you the the link for that
it's really like an introduction to
inventory planner
um webinar that's gonna happen next week
so that's good for
new people on your team or if you're new
to inventory planner
it's a good way to see what the
important sections are how to create
a purchase order go through the major
workflows so definitely check that out
and then at the end of the month we have
a webinar
for advanced forecasting techniques and
so
that'll be a deep dive um really best
for people who have a good handle on
forecasting a good handle on using
inventory planner
and really want to step things up so um
be look
looking forward to that and we'll share
the links in the
chat here and afterwards um with the
webinar
so okay now that we have that stuff out
of the way
here's what we're going to be covering
today so first up we're going to take
just an overall look at your company
and how to get a general sense of what's
the financial health the
inventory related health you know as
inventory
affects the financial health of your
company how do we get a look at those
things um
where are we right now and take a
baseline
then we're going to dig into
replenishment
my experience is there's never enough
money to do everything you want to so
how do we prioritize
what to buy and what can wait so just
figuring out what's most important
in order to get the the maximum
profitability
then we're going to get into overstock i
think overstock's overlooked a lot
but really is important to the financial
health of your company and we'll get
into
more about that um then we'll get into
metrics and reporting
so that you can help coordinate
operations um i know that we may have
people on the call who are a one-person
operation so when you're wearing
different hats
here's where you need to be looking for
different things or if you
do have a bookkeeper an accountant if
you're working with a 3pl you have
somebody in your warehouse we'll talk
about how to coordinate information
across those different areas of your
business
and then finally we'll take a look at
what metrics are available when you're
launching a new product and can
help inform what that initial order for
a new style or a new product is going to
look like
so lots to cover please jump in with
questions
at any time and we'll we'll get going
so first off with the overall health of
your company
so just to lay a baseline and kind of
tell you
about my perspective in coming to this
and kind of sharing with you a few key
metrics to look at
so if we're thinking about our business
as a money machine
we put in one dollar we invest one
dollar and we want to get two dollars
out of that
um and so there's two key parts of this
one we want to turn one dollar into two
dollars as fast as possible we want to
recoup our investment
and if possible we don't just want to
turn it into two dollars we want to turn
it into
three into five into ten dollars um so
the the two part the two key parts of
this are speed of recuperating our
investment and then
maximizing the return on that investment
so in our case we're looking at this the
investment the one dollar that we're
putting into it is our inventory it's
our stock
we're saying here's what we're starting
out with and then on the other side of
things we're looking at
what's the revenue what's the profit
that we can get out of this
so um we want to figure out how do we
maximize that
and how do we get that done as fast as
possible so
the first part so um we're looking at a
general
overview here so we're going to start on
the total level and we'll get into
actual reports within inventory planner
so we're going to start on a total level
because we want the big picture of
what's going on
and then we're going to dig into it at a
category brand or vendor level
i really like to get in on a category
level that's assuming that you have
different types of product within your
company
but i definitely see merchants
especially fashion merchants who are
very brand focused
and this could be true of electronics as
well want to get in and look at either
brand or vendor and that's really what
makes sense for that next
layer down but just know that that will
still give you a big picture look at
things we're not too granular
we can see some good trends that are
going on and really hone in on maybe
some problem areas or maximize things
that are going well
and then we're going to get down into
the product and variant level as we dig
into things more
in terms of terminology product is
everything
if you think about when you're setting
up your website whether that's on
shopify bigcommerce woocommerce the
product page is where that whole
style or um just kind of an overview of
that
product is and then the variant is the
red version the green version the blue
version
each one of those is the variant it's
the most granular level but all of those
live under the product so that's like
the parent the variant is the child
so just make sure we're on the same page
with terminology here
okay so um that the first part of that
money machine equation is speed so
um one metric that we're going to look
at for this is sell through
and i guess another caveat for for what
we're talking through today
um i am simplifying this and just trying
to give you a sense of
what are a couple of key metrics to
really start with and look at
the health of your inventory there's a
lot more that could happen in terms of
other metrics but i'm giving you a
starting place to really say
okay does this look good does this look
bad what's some context to this
so starting with sell-through um
sell-through
is taking your sales meaning number of
units sold and dividing it by the
opening stock
typically you'll you'll look at this
over a month
so let's say that we bought 100 units of
a product
and we sold 20 of them that means we've
only recouped
at 20 you know we we've only sold 20
percent of what we originally bought
unless we have some pretty great margins
we probably haven't even recovered
our original uh investment in that
inventory so that's not looking so great
but if we're getting closer to a hundred
percent that means that we've sold
through
everything that we've purchased and in
fact
so generally the higher the better on
sell through but we can't actually get
to a ceiling on this
you could even go through you could even
be
at more than 100 meaning you're
purchasing a couple of times
a month and going through all of that
inventory and in that case
that might actually be telling you that
there's more
customer demand you might want to be
purchasing more inventory so that you're
not missing out on revenue and running
into stock outs
okay so in general the higher the better
but you can't actually get too high on
that and it could be signaling maybe you
want to raise your prices
and not just purchasing more units so
that's that's something to think about
there
with sell through okay um
and then that number what that tells you
is you may want to take a look at your
replenishment approach um you know so i
mentioned maybe you're purchasing
multiple times
a month you may want to think about
do we purchase more at one time is it
more economical could we get a better
unit price
um and then if your sell through is
too low you want to be looking at your
overstock
what do we have on hand that's not
moving how do we get it out of here
because it's really dragging down that
number
so um that's that's what you can do
about that
um then so we're talking about speed and
now we're looking at maximizing what
we're getting back on that
investment and we're looking at gm roi
so this is gross margin return
on investment what does that mean it
means we're looking at
what is our profit over and above what
our investment was
in that original inventory so that means
okay the
the cost is what we've paid our vendor
once we've recuperated that
anything that the customer pays us then
is our profit so over and above that
and we want to see what is our gross
margin
above our inventory investment so the
gross margin return on investment gm roi
is a good place to get started and take
a look at that
and so we talked at the beginning about
how we'd start at a total level
let's let's get over um into inventory
planner and we can take a look at that
so um the two primary places we're going
to be looking at today
uh here in the replenishment section but
also
here i'm going to come into reports and
then
inventory kpis
so if we look at this let's start on a
total level
and we can look at let's say the
last 30 days and then over here with
this gear icon
here's where we're going to find all of
our metrics that we're talking through
today so
if i'm adding in gm roi i've already got
it in here
it looks like it's down here at the
bottom so i'm actually going to drag and
drop and bring this
up closer to the the front of my report
i've also got sell through so i'm going
to bring that up here too
okay so we're starting on a total level
um and we're taking a look at things so
this 220 percent this is telling us that
we are going through
with that we have a really great return
on investment um our sell through
overall
is 46 so probably not great that means
we have a lot of items
on hand at the end of the month
actually the majority of items that we
had on hand at the beginning of the
month we still have at the end of the
month
so that's probably not great
then we can dig in here and look at a
category level
so we have the big picture now we want
to see what's happening on categories
and this is really nice because then you
can see look at our sell through look at
how different these are by category so
accessories is really bringing up the
end here things are not looking good
here so that might even be a category
that we want to look at
either that we switch those things up in
our in our catalog or even get rid of
that
category because it's performing pretty
poorly
whereas some of our other categories the
men's category here is doing really well
so we'd want to dig into that and figure
out
what's going well what can we repeat
and really scale our business based on
that okay so that's kind of the process
we start a total
category we could even come in on the
variant level here and see what's
driving
that information okay so
that's that's some big picture
information um
what can we do we talked about with the
gm roi so
if that margin is not high enough to
cover all of our expenses you know so
sit down with your bookkeeper and say
what are all our expenses
rent salaries fulfillment cost shipping
costs et cetera
are we covering all of those are we
getting a profit out of this
and if the margin is not sufficient you
really have two options raise your price
or lower your costs
so i know easier said than done but
the raised prices thing um that's
something i had to do as a merchant we
got in and we saw that our most popular
line of products was not even profitable
so we had to raise prices of course we
had upset customers
um but during our customer service
process we were just transparent with
them and saying
um you know unfortunately these were
these were priced too low
in order for us um you know to really be
viable
um and make this work we've got to raise
prices so that didn't make them happy
but they understood i'm just being
transparent about that so
i really feel your um you may need to
dig into that and raise some prices
there also talk to your vendors see if
you can lower costs
um you could be using some forecasting
to let them know what the demand will be
in the future that could be something
that could help them
plan so they can buy it cost or buy at
scale
and pass along some of those costs to
you you could talk about the
ordering in minimums and see if if you
buy more at a time if that lowers the
per unit cost
so those can be some things that can
help you improve
your gm roi
okay um so overall
you know that gives us a sense of what
our company looks like on a total level
maybe a category or vendor level
when we get down to looking at products
we get down to looking
at variants um we can break these down
into a b
and c classes so what does this mean
this is something that's configurable
within inventory planner so if we come
to
account and then settings
and we're going to come over here to
forecast
come all the way to the bottom so a
class means this is our
our best performers this is our first 80
of
our revenue so if you think about what's
the fewest number of variants
that could count towards the first 80
percent of my revenue these are all
going to be a
class items b class in the next 15 and c
class is the final five percent as you
can see this is configurable this is
you're looking at the defaults right now
but you can change this so that your a
class uh could be the top ninety percent
it could be the top fifty percent
just know whatever makes sense for your
company and you can really divide things
up that way
um by default we're looking at the last
30 days
this can be good if you are looking at
non-seasonal selling
but if you have a seasonal business you
should probably move this over to the
last 365 days because if you have
great performers um that really take off
in the fourth quarter
we're looking at the last 30 days
obviously we're missing that so
if you change that over to the last 365
days
then you'll get their performance last
fourth quarter as we head into
fourth quarter for this year okay so
that's abc analysis that'll help you
look at your
catalog and we'll get into kind of how
that applies
once we get into the replenishment and
the overstock
a little bit later but this can be this
can help in kind of cleaning up your
product
catalog so let's dig into
the replenishment so um just in case you
don't have a money tree
outside your window um how do you
prioritize what to buy
so in this webinar we're not going
through
the forecast methods and settings of
inventory planner that's the webinar
next week
so i'm setting aside a lot of
information
for this webinar but tune in next week
if you want to get caught up on that so
um so we're coming into this saying that
we have
already fine-tuned our forecast methods
for each of these items we have our lead
time and days of stock
set up and we've got our replenishment
this is showing the number of units we
need to buy
in order to meet customer demand during
this time
so if we order today on the 10th we'll
get these items on september 24th
and then when they arrive on september
24th they'll last until october 24th
so from today until october 24th
that is our planning period and this
will recommend
enough units so that we can meet all of
the customer demand we're not going to
miss out on revenue
during that whole time so um
it's not enough though to look at this
column and say
okay well this is the highest number of
units so i should get that
i mean i think that you can see where
this is going um
that items are going to have different
profitability and so i think it's really
helpful to look at
replenishment profit and i'm going to
scroll to the right here
so basically we're taking the profit per
unit
and multiplying that by the number of
units that were recommended to purchase
so here's our profitability so if we
click on the column title here and sort
we will actually see that because items
have
different profitability we'll see that
for example here's an item that has 312
units that were recommended to purchase
there's fewer number of units that we
need for some of these other ones but we
have higher profitability
so if we didn't order those items here's
the profit we're missing out on this is
really focused on that
how do we maximize what comes out of the
money machine are we getting two dollars
three dollars five dollars
okay so prioritize here to really say
um we're making the most of our
inventory investment
okay so that's replenishment profit then
the next one is
um the newest metric within inventory
planner and hopefully
many of you read your newsletter that we
sent out last week
announcing this new metric
so we've got two order which is really
related to the replenishment
column that we see here in inventory
planner
and i'm going to add another couple of
columns here so that we can see
how this is generated and really what it
means
but this is taking a look at that
original replenishment recommendation
that we had
that the the formula is saying here's
how many we need
right um and then two order is saying
okay but we have some vendor
considerations
so these could be minimums so here's our
minimum order quantity we can see we
originally suggested to order about 1800
units but
our minimum on this item is 3 000. so we
can see that
when this actually gets to the purchase
order it would need to be 3 000 units
okay so that's a pretty different story
and that gives us more information to
say okay i'm going to need to
have more on hand i'm going to need to
over order actually
if i'm complying with these vendor
minimums and if i place this order right
now
and just weighing out what does that
mean in terms of recuperating my
investment
here um another consideration that two
order takes into consideration
is uom which is units of
measurement this is our case size this
means
i have to order 25 of these at a time i
can't order them in singles
so i can't order 1202
we have to order in multiples of 25. you
can see that we're rounding up here and
that'll be 1225.
okay so that just gives us a sense of
what are those vendor constraints
that are put on our original
recommendation
to see what we would really put on a
purchase order
and i think hopefully you saw when i was
adding to order
there's some related metrics so we can
look at the cost price of what that will
be so we have the two order which is
units
and we can see what that would be on a
purchase order as well as the
profitability
so um hopefully that will help
especially if you're dealing with those
those vendor constraints on your order
all right then a very common question
that we get is how do i tell
how long my stock will last and there's
a family of metrics that are very
similar but i want to walk through how
they're different so that they can tell
you
exactly the information that you need
okay
so the first one here is stock cover
and stock cover is truly just the stock
on hand i have 10 units
in my warehouse here's how long the 10
units are going to last
pretty straightforward and we've got
this available in stock cover
in days weeks or months
so you can really break down how you
need to see that information
okay so i think that's the most
straightforward we're going to get into
some pictures
for uh to help illustrate cells out in
first and cells out in
so both of these second the second and
third metrics listed here
consider yes the the 10 units that we
have in our warehouse but we've also got
10 units on a purchase order
so we're committed to 20 units total and
we want to know how long those last
there's a little bit of difference
between these two so first
let's say that it's july 1st our current
stock
we're going to be able to look at that
with stock covering days that's just the
10 units in our warehouse
and our purchase order isn't going to
arrive until september 1st
that means we've got a gap we're
actually going to be out of stock for
the whole month of august
sells out in first tells us the first
day
that we're going to be out of stock and
that we're going to have
outs so um
sells ozone first is going to tell us
august 1st for that date
sells out in looks at the farthest out
date of all the stock that we're cons
that we're uh committed to so the 10
that we have on hand the 10 on the
purchase order
what's the last day that that's going to
last through regardless of if we have
stock outs in the meantime
that's sells addend that's going to tell
us october 1st okay
so we can see here how sells out in
first has the first day we're running
out and then
october 1st is with the sells out in is
basically the last day that all of that
stock is going to last
so this is the situation where we have a
gap before our purchase order arrives
but what if we don't have a gap uh we'll
get that purchase order before we run
out of our current stock
so you can see there's an overlap in
stock um
no stockouts are happening here in this
case sells out in first and sells out in
are gonna tell us the same date okay
because there's no break in the action
um that would kind of trigger that cells
out in first to to show earlier
um so that's when they're gonna show for
the same date
so that's that's a quick explanation of
that family
of of metrics very common question that
we get
just to see what's the current state of
things uh
what basically like what kind of
emergency do i have in placing
my purchase order i think is what people
are getting out there
so um and you can see all of these in
the replenishment report we've got cells
out in
that is showing by default um so you can
see the date
as well as the number of days until
you're gonna run out of stock
and anything on order so that's what
that sells out and is telling us here
all right so that's a bit about how to
replenish
prioritize replenishment um i know that
we went through that quickly
definitely pop in with some questions if
you want to know more about that or have
other
considerations within your store we can
definitely talk through your situation
so now we're going to get into overstock
so so rightly so
um the replenishment piece of things is
the first
item of business it's where we pay
attention to first so that we're not
missing out on revenue
once that's under control please pay
attention to overstock i think it's it's
less exciting it's not new it's not
flashy
but in terms of the the effect of
inventory on your company's financial
health
it really has a large effect um
and even if you think it's just sitting
on your warehouse shelves it's not
really doing any harm
um it can be doing something for you and
it can be costing you
actual money we're gonna talk through
this so
a couple key metrics to look at with
overstock are both
overstock retail and cost this means the
retail value of all the units that are
overstock as well as the cost value
and the reason i say looking at both of
these is because often
not always but often getting rid of
overstock means discounting
so it could be that the actual money
we'll get out of these items is
somewhere in between the retail and the
cost
values so within inventory planner we're
going to come here to the overstock
report now this is going to use all of
the same forecasting methods and
settings
that we have in by default on our
account settings as well as any
customizations that we might have made
back here in
the replenishment page and so remember
that the planning period that we were
looking at
says that we are looking to plan through
october 24th
so this says here's how many units that
you are forecast to have on hand
as of october 24th okay so
here's the number of units this may look
like a lot but we need more context
because we don't know
maybe this is a hot seller and that's
just two weeks of overstock which is
like
not great but not awful right i don't
need to come up with a separate campaign
i can probably just wait it out and wait
for that over stock
um to go away but it could be that 5200
units is 18 months worth of overstock in
which case that's that's a problem and
we need to put some special effort into
that so we need more context
on what's going on so here's the
overstock retail that we talked about
again with the gear icon you can add in
overstock cost
to see how much can we potentially get
out of this
and then one other thing that i want you
to look at in the overstock here
is these labels so this is telling us
more about
how long are these items going to last
so you can see we have 17
18 months on a lot of these so we're
really overstocked
um the the the ceiling on our program
um is actually what's showing here is is
18 months so it could last even longer
so this is really a problem this will
help give you some more information
if you haven't already it can be helpful
to connect
google analytics to your inventory
planner account this will show you
metrics like page views
and conversion rates and it will add
additional labels here which i think can
be really
helpful so when we're when we're
thinking about overstock sometimes we
know
why things are overstocked you know we
um
trends change within the market or a
marketing campaign didn't work out or
um whatever it might be sometimes we
know sometimes we don't know
why things are overstocked and that
information i think especially from
google analytics can give us
more context so for example
if we see something that says low
conversion rate
that tells us we've got some traffic
coming to that page
but it's not converting so what can we
do about that we could maybe look at a
new product
image we could look at tweaking the
title you know maybe it's something to
do with the
pricing um but we know that there's
traffic there how can we make more use
of it so it's just like one more piece
to the puzzle
to help figure out why these are
overstocked and how we can get some
items
out of there so that's a that's a quick
look
at overstock here
all right um one other piece when you're
looking at overstock
is the aging analysis so we're going to
come down here
to reports and then come to aging
analysis and what this
is telling us is how long have items
actually been on hand since we received
them on a purchase order
so if you're brand new to inventory
planner you'll probably see that
everything is here in the 0 to 30 days
column we're collecting this information
as
you are using inventory planner longer
so that's how we're able to track
your your stock history in stock detail
there and so you'll see this populate
over time the longer you're using
inventory planner but what this is
telling us
is some of these items have been around
over a year
from six to 12 months um and this is
helpful
not just for people who might have
perishable items with a shelf life but
also think about if you
are selling something that's trendy or
part of your marketing strategy is to
have
new and fresh things in front of your
customers it's been around a year
it's not new it's not fresh it needs to
get out of there
also think about this is where it could
literally be costing you money
is if you are using a third-party
logistics company
if you are selling on amazon shipping
fba
you're paying long-term storage fees or
you're paying storage fees to have those
items on the shelf
you're paying to have this there that
long without getting
so not only have you invested in the
inventory but you are paying
to have it sit on a shelf get it out of
there
move it out um so this is a this is a
time where we'll take that strategy
again here we're looking at total
let's dig down into what are some of
these items you know to look at even
specific variants for what are these
oldest items
um and really like focus on getting
those out of there
so this is the aging analysis this
assumes first in first out and this
information is based on what's happening
with your your purchase order receiving
okay so now let's get into
coordinating operations so uh
here's where you make friends with your
bookkeeper your bookkeeper is going to
love this part
so we're getting into
your bookkeeper is probably asking you
for
the stock cost on a monthly basis
meaning the cost price is what you pay
your vendor and they want to know
what's what's the total of that for
everything you still have on hand in
your warehouse
okay so you can see this every day uh
here on the overview
here's the stock cost meaning the cost
value of all of your inventory
and this is as of today if you're like
me i always forgot to look on the day
and so i have to go back and look
at what was happening on the last day of
the prior month
okay so let's walk through how to find
that information too
so we're going to come to reports and
come into
inventory kpis and so
here's a situation where we're going to
look at this on a total basis
i think typically your bookkeeper is
going to want this on a total basis
probably not on a category basis um and
then we're going to
look at last month because they're
closing out the books for august
right now and then what we're looking
for here is
closing stock costs the closing part of
this means it corresponds
to the last date of our report
here okay so similarly if we added
opening stock cost that would correspond
here to august 1st but we need that
closing stock cost so
now i've added that so now i can report
to my bookkeeper here is the slo
closing stock cost of what we had on
hand on august 31st
so that he or she can close out the
books for august
okay um so that's making things
easier hopefully for your life and your
bookkeepers um
other related reports so we do have a
stock history report
this will show you the value of your
inventory as of the first date
of each month so here we have this in
units we have that cost value and then
at retail meaning what your customers
could purchase um so this is again the
first day of the month this is the month
view we also
in this report have this available by
week
so you can see this here on a retail
weekly
calendar so that's available for you
to help coordinate with your bookkeeper
or accountant
another piece of information that
bookkeepers and accountants often want
to know
are cost of goods sold now
public service announcement um terms
that are commonly
used interchangeably but are actually
different are cost
and cogs or cost of cost of goods sold
those are two different things
so let's walk through cost value means
the price per unit that you would pay
your vendor so that's the price per unit
you see on your purchase order
okay cogs is think about what
i mean spell out the acronym cost of
goods sold or think about
cost of all goods sold so that's the
cumulative total
of each of those cost prices for
everything that you
sold okay so again you can come to
the inventory kpis you can look at this
on a total basis
and um i believe yep we have cost of
goods sold
already enabled here so we can see that
on a total basis
so you can see this will be
corresponding to all the sales we had
during this period what was the cost
value of all of those items so this is
looking at are we recoupering
recuperating our inventory investment
during that time
here's what that corresponds to
okay so that ends my public service
announcement
on cost price versus cost of goods sold
please note let me know if you have any
questions about that
and then we can use the terms correctly
okay so um
one last one for your accountant and
bookkeeper
coming to reports and then good received
note
so this corresponds to your purchase
orders and this says
here's how much we received during
certain months
and by supplier i think this will
typically be what your account or
bookkeeper is looking for is
by vendor or by supplier how much did we
receive
so number of units but also the cost
value of that
so this can just help you reconcile what
happened between the purchase orders
that might be in your accounting system
and what you actually
received so this is a good way to make
sure everybody's on
the same page okay so now that you're a
bookkeeper
and accountant are really happy and
you're happy because you can easily get
this information
for them let's go over
to another area of your operations
receiving and warehouse so this could be
in-house this could be a separate 3pl
that you're using
especially if you're using a 3pl they
very often want to know
what is coming who's it coming from how
much is coming
okay so that's like the constant battle
with the 3pl is figuring out
are we on the same page do they know
what to expect
so just as this good receive note looks
historically at what those purchase
orders were that came
in we have a compliment to that called
the delivery schedule so that's going to
look in the future
at what all of these purchase orders are
that are
open they're scheduled um we've placed
these with the vendor and here's when we
expect them
so inventory planner users be sure that
you're paying attention to that expected
arrival date as you're looking at
drafting your purchase order so by
default it's based on your lead time but
if there are special considerations
it's really important to update that so
that we're getting
accurate forecasting information for you
but also then it's reflected
accurately here on the purchase order
delivery schedule
so this will show okay from our us
supplier here's how many units we're
expecting
within september if your 3pl needs more
information needs more detail
okay is that in three shipments is that
in one shipment then you can come back
here to
your purchase order and transfer section
and you can actually pull a report for
them
that will show okay let's come up here
and use
our filters we're going to say okay just
from this supplier
and then we're going to look at expected
date is
from today through the end of the month
and we'll apply those filters and then
we'll be able to say
okay here are the purchase orders that
are coming we could even filter them by
the destination warehouse so for a
particular location
here's how much is coming and then from
here you can export
um this top item purchase order list
will basically be a reflection of what
we see
on the screen now it's really a summary
the second option is looking at
each item and how many of each of those
items is listed so this will be a lot
more detailed purchase order line items
okay so that will give you a spreadsheet
that you can share with them
to get that information so
that's looking at how to get everybody
on the same page in terms
of operations all right last section
before we dig
into some questions is um so inventory
planners set up really to make
recommendations for
replenishing meaning we have sales
history on items
we know some of their behavior and so we
can make a recommendation on what that
looks like
obviously with new products we don't
have that data so
we're flying blind a little bit but
there are some reports there are some
metrics that can give us
more information so that we can make a
more educated
guess about what that initial order will
look like for new products
so for that we're going to come back
over here so
under reports we're going to look at the
assortment report
so um this we're going to talk through a
couple use cases here so the first is
really like how do we get this
information for our new
products so we want to think about our
new products that we're looking at
what things do they have in common with
items that we
already sell that we do have data on
okay so we're trying to think about what
what do they have in common
so one thing we're going to do here is
the view for
this we're going to come into option
sets
so this goes back to your home platform
this means all those drop downs on the
product page
color size flavor any of those drop
downs that your customers choose from
each of those are option sets and so we
show performance
per option set here so let's come in and
look at how each of the different colors
that we
present to customers how those perform
okay
so sales uh for inventory planner that's
number of units
here's how those sell we can see that
this is sorted by revenue
so we have a sense of that this is
looking at our whole store though
which which is helpful but again try to
think about our new product
how similar is it to something that we
already have
so can we add additional filters for
a certain category because we know that
we're going to be launching this in the
dress category
or do you have certain tags vendors you
know think about how you can kind of
whittle this down to make it as similar
as possible
to data that we already have and then
this tells us okay within the dress
category
here's how these different colors
perform and then i can
create that initial order and say all
right well orange is our top performing
color so we need
the most of those on our new order for
our new item
followed by green purple etc okay so
this is just helping to paint the
picture
and say here's some data we do have
okay so that's one use for this a
certain assortment report which
hopefully can help you
figure out how many and of what
to purchase for your new items
another use of the assortment report
and this is this is not necessarily for
new items but is looking at
just overall how do we figure out what
the performance of our store
is so if we're looking at categories
we're looking at you know performance
across all of our categories well maybe
i want to see
how one of my suppliers one of my
vendors performs
across all of these categories so i'm
going to come in here and add a filter
for
the us supplier
apply that filter now i can see the
performance
of this supplier across all of my
categories so here's the revenue that's
coming in here's
the number of units we're selling the
sales
for this supplier so this is another way
that we can see
how is this vendor really performing for
us um again you could bring in different
filters so this could be
tags brands um you could even filter
down by warehouse we're looking
you know at a combined view here so
there's a lot of ways that you could
really kind of like
slice and dice this information to get
a better sense of what's happening
across your shore for
performance so um
that wraps up um a whirlwind look at
different metrics and reporting
available within
inventory planner i think i saw some
questions pop up during the during the
talk
so feel free to either add more
questions or or more in the chat
um and we can we can walk through those
all right basil did we have any
questions come in
or something happening during the talk
there
i had one question that i did answer
i'm just about importing units of
measurement and moq
i haven't seen others do feel free to
type into the qa box if you have
questions
uh of course if you're digesting this
incredible information that jill has
offered you
definitely feel free to keep exploring
you're always going to find us there at
the bottom right chat box
you'll find a ton of useful articles and
and you can always ask us questions
there so we'll be happy to guide you to
some of the right information or
instructions to kind of help get
some of this in place we do have another
question here we go
up will we get a copy of the session to
watch again
yes definitely so it is being recorded
you'll get
an automatic um link to this sent to you
within 24 hours
we're also going to post it on our
youtube channel so it'll be available
there
if you haven't checked out our youtube
channel we have a lot of information
so we've got other webinars that are
recorded there so you can see
long form content and really like a deep
dive into things
we've got quick tip videos so those are
two minutes or less to really take a
look at quick things that are happening
um for better use of inventory planner
we've got things
related to general forecasting that's
not even specific to inventory planner
so definitely check that out and as
always just let us know what other
content that you would like to know um
one thing
i was just remembering that i forgot to
mention during this session
that's applicable right now as we're
looking towards the holidays
um so remember you're looking at your
margins you're looking at what your
profitability is
oftentimes during the holidays you're
offering discounts so just
factor that in when you're planning your
your margins and your profitability and
your cash flow
during the fourth quarter that that
could take a hit due to promotions that
you're running it may not look like the
rest of the year
um in terms of what those margins are so
just one thing to keep in mind right now
as you're planning for the rest of the
year
all right um i think that you said we
had a question about
um uom and moq
so here in the catalog you can manage a
lot of information about
your your items and so if you come here
to vendor attributes that's where you're
going to see that moq
and uon field and even if there are
items where you can source from more
than one supplier so that's what these
top couple of items are showing us so
we've got one item
it can come from either one of these
suppliers
so we could have different cost prices
we could have different references
different product names
and different
moqs and uom for each one of those so
you can see
that you know we could put in maybe we
have to order in
multiples of 10 from this supplier but
multiples
of 25 from another supplier so all of
that can be customized
if you're able to source from more than
one vendor for
for one item
all right well if we don't have
any other questions i think we'll just
um wrap things up
again you will get the recording of this
um always let us know what other
sessions you want we will follow up with
links to
other sessions that we have coming up
both next week and at the end of the
month
and thanks so much for joining us today